Harriet F. Pilpel Papers, 1913-1981
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
Harriet F. Pilpel papers
1913-1981
Pilpel, Harriet F.
MS 311 UUID:aa2cd39f-9415-4def-afdf-bc957c0b0eec
28 boxes (13.75 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Lawyer; birth control advocate; and abortion rights advocate. The Harriet F. Pilpel Papers are primarily related to her professional work with sexual and reproductive rights. The collection is essentially Pilpel's reference files, and is primarily composed of court documents from various legal cases on the state and federal level. The papers allow for a comprehensive, state-to-state comparison of a variety of sexual and reproductive laws, and provides a sense of the debates going on in individual states and the country regarding sexual and reproductive issues. Materials include correspondence, memoranda, press releases, reports, legislation, notes, journal and newspaper articles, and court documents.
Harriet Fleischl Pilpel was born in New York City in 1911 to businessperson Julius and Ethel (Loewy) Fleischl. She was graduated from Vassar in 1932 and received a Master's degree in 1933 and a law degree in 1936, both from Columbia University.
She married Robert Pilpel, a social service executive on June 15, 1933. They had two children, Judith Ethel Pilpel Appelaum and Robert Harry Pilpel.
Harriet Pilpel was a member of the New York Bar and senior partner in the law firm of Greenbaum, Wolff & Ernst who specialized in First Amendment issues. Between 1937 and 1991, she participated in twenty-seven cases before the U.S. Supreme Court. A prolific lecturer and author of publications related to copyright, abortion, marriage, birth control, civil liberties, and the law, she was also active in many organizations including the board of directors of Planned Parenthood Federation of America for whom she was legal counsel. Pilpel was also counsel to a number of other associations, including Sex Information and Educational Council of the United States, Association for the Study of Abortion, and Association for Voluntary Sterilization. In addition, she served on the boards of the National Abortion Rights Action League, the American Civil Liberties Union, and The Alan Guttmacher Institute. She died in her sleep April 23, 1991.
The Harriet F. Pilpel Papers consist of 13.75 linear feet and are primarily related to her professional work with sexual and reproductive rights, dating from 1913 to 1981. The bulk of the papers date from 1966-81 and focus on sexual rights and liberties. The collection is essentially Pilpel's reference files, and is primarily composed of court documents from various legal cases on the state and federal level, as well as newspaper clippings and articles. There is very little personal correspondence or other materials that are not accessible through the public domain in the collection. However, the files allow for a comprehensive, state-to-state comparison of a variety of sexual and reproductive laws, and provide a sense of the debates going on in individual states and the country regarding sexual and reproductive issues. Types of material include correspondence, memoranda, press releases, reports, legislation, notes, journal and newspaper articles, and court documents.
Major topics found throughout these papers include family planning, abortion, contraception, sterilization, as well as the funding of these activities. Related topics include consent and notification for family planning activities, distribution and advertisements related to sex, sexual activities, and the sexual and reproductive rights of minors. The subject "reproductive rights" serves as an all-inclusive category that contains information about subjects such as maternity rights and population, as well as materials related to several aspects of sexual rights and liberties. "Minors" includes all subjects related to minors except the sterilization of mentally incompetent minors, which is located with the materials related to the sterilization of the mentally incompetent. Organizations represented include the American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU); National Abortion Rights Action League (NARAL); Planned Parenthood Federation of America (PPFA), briefly known as Planned Parenthood-World Population; the Association for the Study of Abortion; and the Association for Voluntary Sterilization. Prominent Supreme Court cases documented include Griswold v. Connecticut (1965), United States v. Vuitch (1971), Eisenstadt v. Baird (1972), Roe v. Wade (1973) and Doe v. Bolton (1973), Bellotti v. Baird (1975), T.H. v. Jones (1975), Planned Parenthood of Central Missouri v. Danforth (1976), and Carey v. Populations Services International (1977).
This collection is organized into two series:
I. United States
II. Individual States and Territories
III. International
Oversize Materials
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The Harriet F. Pilpel Papers are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection.
History of the Collection
Harriet F. Pilpel donated her research files to the Sophia Smith Collection in 1982.
Search Terms
Abortion--Law and legislation--United States--History--Sources; American Civil Liberties Union--History--Sources; Birth control--Developing countries--History--20th century--Sources; Birth control--Law and legislation--United States--History--Sources; Edelin, Kenneth, 1939-; Minors-Civil rights-United States--History--20th century--Sources; National Abortion Rights Action League--History; Pilpel, Harriet F.; Planned Parenthood Federation of America--History--Sources; Planned Parenthood-World Population (U.S.)--History--Sources; Population policy--History--20th century--Sources; Reproductive health-United States--History--20th century--Sources; Roe, Jane, 1947- --Trials, litigation, etc.; Sterilization (birth control)--History--Sources; Tietze, Christopher, 1908-; Wade, Henry--Trials, litigation, etc.; Women--Legal status, laws, etc.--History--20th century--Sources
Additional Information
Related Material
Other materials related to Pilpel within the Sophia Smith Collection can be found in the Florence Rose Papers, the Dorothy Kenyon Papers, and the records of the Planned Parenthood Federation of America (PPFA). Many of Pilpel's works are available in the Five College Libraries. Additional Harriet Pilpel papers are housed at the Arthur and Elizabeth Schlesinger Library on the History of Women in America at Radcliffe College.
- SERIES I. UNITED STATES 1937-81, 4 linear ft.
  This series provides an overview of sexual and reproductive liberties on a national level during the late 1960s and 1970s. The series is arranged alphabetically by subject, and chronologically within each folder. The bulk of this series is composed of material that covers more than one state or discusses a subject from the national perspective. Abortion, contraception, and the rights of minors can be examined on a state-to-state basis. Federal legislation and materials related to national organizations, including the ACLU, NARAL, and PPFA form a large part of this series. All of the cases that have been heard by the Supreme Court are found within this series, and include all materials related to lower court decisions. Cases that the Supreme Court refused to hear can be found in SERIES II. INDIVIDUAL STATES AND TERRITORIES. The subject categories "families and family law" and "status of women" cover both state and national topics. "Civil rights and liberties" includes material on a wide variety of subjects not related to gender or sexual rights. The only biographical material related to Harriet Pilpel is found under the organization, Sex Information and Education Council of the United States.
- SERIES II. INDIVIDUAL STATES AND TERRITORIES 1913-81, 9.25 linear ft.
  This series comprises the bulk of the collection and covers topics related to sexual rights and liberties within each of the states and territories. The materials are arranged in alphabetical order first by state or territory, and then by topic within each state or territory. New York, Massachusetts, and Michigan form the largest portions of the series. Most of the daily transcripts from Commonwealth of Massachusetts vs. Edelin, a widely publicized trial of an abortion doctor accused of manslaughter in 1975, are also included. [Note: The transcripts from days two through four and fifteen are missing.] In 1971, Pilpel worked on a Health, Education, and Welfare survey that compared family planning and reproductive rights laws in each of the states and territories. The results of that survey, as well as the correspondence relating to it, are found in most of the states and territories under reproductive rights. Many court cases at both the state and district court levels can be found within this series under the subject of the case.
- SERIES III. INTERNATIONAL 1967-79, .5 linear ft.
  This series examines sexual rights and liberties as well as the status of women around the world during the 1970s. The categories "abortion," "family planning and population programs," "sterilization," and the "status of women" are predominantly composed of articles and newspaper clippings. If a document discusses more than one country or looks at a subject from a global perspective, it is located within the general files under the subject. If the focus of an article is specific to one country, then it is filed under the individual country. The names of individual countries are arranged in alphabetical order
- SERIES I. UNITED STATES 1937-81
  - Abortion
    - General, 1964-80 (Box 1, Folder 1-7)
    - Facilities and staff, 1971-76, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Funding, 1971-77 (Box 2, Folder 2-4)
    - Model statute, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Paternal rights (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - State action, 1974-75 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Contraception
    - Advertisements and distribution
      - General, 1973-76 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Emko mailings, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Comstock laws, 1965-68 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - State contraception laws, 1937-38 (Box 2, Folder 11-14)
    - State to state comparison, 1971-72 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - Types of, 1970-75 (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  - Families and family law, 1968-79, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Family planning, 1970-80, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Federal legislation, 1970-75 (Box 3, Folder 7-9)
    - Bartlett Amendment, 1974-75 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Hogan Amendment, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Health insurance, 1972-76, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Homosexuality, 1974-76 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Minors, 1971-79, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Advertising abortion and contraception information, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Consent for medical treatment, 1972-75, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Contraception, 1969-74, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - State to state comparison, 1972-77 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - Reproductive rights, General, 1971-77 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Military, 1971-78 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      [See also SERIES III. International-Indochina]
    - Organizations, 1938-79 (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
      [See also Oversize Materials]
      - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), 1973-80 (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
      - Association for the Study of Abortion (ASA) newsletter, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - National Abortion Rights Action League (NARAL), 1972-79 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Planned Parenthood Federation of America (PPFA), 1961-81 (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
        [See also Supreme Court--Planned Parenthood of Central Missouri v. Danforth]
      - Planned Parenthood--World Population (PPWP), 1965-80 (Box 5, Folder 5-7)
      - Sex and Education Information Council of the United States (SEICUS), 1973 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Rights and liberties, 1972-79 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Status of women
    - General, 1973-77 (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
    - President's Commission, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Sterilization
    - General, 1967-79 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Involuntary, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Mentally incompetent, 1972-78 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Voluntary, 1971-79 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Supreme Court of the United States
    - Anders v. Floyd (1979), 1975-77 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Ashcroft v. Freiman (1979), 1978-79 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Beal v. Franklin (1978), 1974-78 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Bellotti v. Baird (1975, 1979), 1975-78 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Bigelow v. Commonwealth of Virginia (1975), 1971-75 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Califano v. McRae (1977), 1976-79 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Carey v. Population Services International (1977), 1975-79 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    - Connecticut v. Menillo (1975), 1975 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Doe v. Beal (1977), 1975 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Doe v. Bolton (1973), 1970-73 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      [See also Roe v. Wade]
    - Doe v. Planned Parenthood Association of Utah (1973), 1972-73 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Eisenstadt v. Baird (1972), 1970-73 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Griswold v. Connecticut (1965), 1964-65 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - H. L. v. Matheson (1981), 1979-80 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Maher v. Roe (1977), 1976-77, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Nashville Gas Company v. Satty (1977), 1977 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Planned Parenthood of Central Missouri v. Danforth (1976), 1974-1976 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Roe v. Wade (1973), 1970-73, undated (Box 8, Folder 2-3)
    - Singleton v. Wulff (1976), 1974-75 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Spannaus v. Hodgson (1975), 1974-75 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - T.H. v. Jones (1975), 1975-77 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - United States v. Vuitch (1971) 1969-72 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Virginia State Board of Pharmacy v. Virginia Citizens Consumer Council (1976), 1976 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Withrow v. Larkin (1975), 1974 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- SERIES II. INDIVIDUAL STATES AND TERRITORIES 1913-81
  - Alabama
    - Abortion
      - Anti-abortion statute, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Funding, 1977-78 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Staff and facilities, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Distribution of literature, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Minors, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Sterilization
      - Involuntary, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Mentally incompetent, 1969-79 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Negligence, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Alaska
    - Abortion, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Minors, 1969, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Reproductive rights, 1971, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - American Samoa, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Arkansas
    - Abortion, 1973-1978 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Contraception, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Minors, 1968, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Reproductive rights, 1971, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Sterilization, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Arizona
    - Abortion, 1971-75 (Box 9, Folder 18-19)
    - Contraception, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Minors, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Reproductive rights, 1962-78 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - California
    - Abortion
      - General, 1967-78 (Box 9, Folder 23-24)
      - Funding, 1977-79, undated (Box 9, Folder 25-26)
    - Contraception, 1974-77 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Family planning, 1970-80 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Minors
      - General, 1970-77 (Box 9, Folder 29)
      - Contraception, 1971-75 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Reproductive rights
      - General, 1971-77 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Laws and legal codes, 1971-77, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Planned Parenthood Affiliates of California (PPAC), 1975-81 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Public Education & Research Committee of California (PERCC), 1974-75 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Sterilization
      - General, 1976-77 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Involuntary, 1975-77, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Mentally incompetent, 1974-81 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Voluntary, 1968, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Colorado
    - Abortion, 1970-73, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Contraception, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Minors, 1975-76 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Reproductive rights, 1969-71 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Connecticut
    - Abortion
      [See also SERIES I. UNITED STATES-Supreme Court- Connecticut v. Menillo; Maher v. Roe ]
      - General, 1968-79 (Box 10, Folder 13-14)
      - Funding, 1974-80 (Box 10, Folder 15-16)
    - Consent, 1975-79 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Contraception, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
      [See also SERIES I. UNITED STATES-Supreme Court-Griswold v. Connecticut]
    - Family planning, 1972, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Minors, 1972-76 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Sterilization
      - Mentally incompetent, 1977-79 (Box 10, Folder 21)
      - Voluntary, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Delaware
    - Abortion, 1973-76, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Minors, 1976, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Reproductive rights, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Sterilization, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - District of Columbia
    - Abortion
      [See also SERIES I. UNITED STATES-Supreme Court-United States v. Vuitch]
      - General, 1970-79 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Anniversary of Roe v. Wade, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Facilities and staff, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Consent, 1972-76 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Family planning, 1971-74 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Minors, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Reproductive rights, 1971-76 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Sterilization, 1973-74 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Florida
    - Abortion
      - General, 1971-80 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Facilities and staff, 1973-79 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Consent, 1973-79 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Contraception, 1972-74 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Family planning, 1972-77 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Minors, 1972-75 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Reproductive rights, 1971-79 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Sterilization, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Georgia
    - Abortion
      [See also SERIES I. UNITED STATES-Supreme Court-Doe v. Bolton]
      - General, 1970-75, undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - Funding, 1977-80 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Minors, 1972, undated (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Sterilization, 1976-77, undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Guam, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Hawaii
    - Abortion, 1970-73 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Minors
      - General, 1972-77 (Box 11, Folder 27)
      - Contraception, 1977-78 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Reproductive rights, 1972-73 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Sterilization, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Idaho
    - Abortion
      - General, 1973-77 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Funding, 1976-77 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Contraception, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Minors, 1971, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Reproductive rights, 1971-79 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Illinois
    - Abortion
      - General, 1970-81 (Box 12, Folder 6-7)
      - Funding, 1978-79 (Box 12, Folder 8-9)
      - Newspaper clippings and articles (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Minors
      - General, 1978-80 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Contraception, 1969, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Reproductive rights, 1971-77 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Sterilization, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Indiana
    - Abortion, 1972-80 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Reproductive rights, 1971-79 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Sterilization, 1976-78 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Iowa
    - Abortion, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Minors, undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Reproductive rights, 1971-79 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Kansas
    - Abortion, 1969-81 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Family planning, 1972-76 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Minors
      - General, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 23)
      - Contraception, 1972-76 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Reproductive rights, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Kentucky
    - Abortion
      - General, 1973-78 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
      - Facilities and staff, 1973-80 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Family planning, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Minors, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Louisiana
    - Abortion
      - General, 1973-80 (Box 13, Folder 6-8)
      - Facilities and staff, 1970-78 (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Funding, 1975-80 (Box 13, Folder 10-11)
    - Consent, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Minors, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Reproductive rights, 1969-73 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Maine
    - Abortion, 1973, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Minors, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Sterilization, 1977-78 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Maryland
    - Abortion
      - General, 1968-77 (Box 13, Folder 18)
      - Facilities and staff, 1971-73 (Box 13, Folder 19)
      - Funding, 1977-79, undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Family Planning Training Institute, 1973-77 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Minors
      - General, 1972-77 (Box 13, Folder 22)
      - Contraception, undated (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Reproductive rights, 1971, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Sterilization, 1971-78 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Massachusetts
    - Abortion, 1972-80, undated (Box 13, Folder 26)
      - Commonwealth of Massachusetts vs. Kenneth Edelin 1975 (Box 14-17)
      - Consent, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 1)
        [See also Minors]
        - Spousal, 1974-76 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Facilities and Staff, 1969-78 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Funding, 1971-81 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Contraception, 1937-38, 1969-77, undated (Box 18, Folder 5-6)
      [See also SERIES I. UNITED STATES-Supreme Court-Eisenstadt v. Baird]
    - Minors, 1972-78, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
      [See SERIES I. UNITED STATES-Supreme Court-Bellotti v. Baird]
    - Reproductive rights, 1971-78 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Sterilization, 1973-78 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Michigan
    - Abortion
      - General, 1972-78 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Facilities and staff, 1972-73, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Funding, 1975-79 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Contraception, 1913, 1971, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Minors
      - General, 1975-78 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Contraception, 1974-77 (Box 19, Folder 6-10)
    - Paternal rights, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Reproductive rights
      - General, 1974-79 (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - Michigan Reproductive Health Rights Council, 1977-79, undated (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - Statutes, 1972-74, undated (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Sterilization
      - Negligence, 1978-79 (Box 19, Folder 15)
      - Voluntary, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Minnesota
    - Abortion
      [See also SERIES I. UNITED STATES-Supreme Court--Spannaus v. Hodgson]
      - General, 1974-78 (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
      - Facilities and staff, 1973-78 (Box 20, Folder 3-4)
      - Funding, 1976-80 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Contraception, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Minors
      - General, 1971-81 (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Contraception, 1972-76 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Reproductive rights, 1974-80 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Sterilization, 1974-78 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Mississippi
    - Abortion, 1966-77, undated (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Advertising, 1975-76 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Reproductive rights, 1972-73 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Missouri
    - Abortion
      [See also SERIES I. UNITED STATES-Supreme Court-- Planned Parenthood of Missouri v. Danforth; Singleton v. Wulff; Ashcroft v. Freiman ]
      - General, 1972-79, undated (Box 20, Folder 14)
      - Facilities and staff, 1972-80 (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - Funding, 1974-80 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Minors, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Reproductive rights, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Sterilization, 1974-79 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Montana
    - Abortion
      - General, 1973-77 (Box 20, Folder 20-21)
      - Facilities and staff, 1973-75 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Contraception, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Sterilization
      - Mentally incompetent, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 24)
      - Voluntary, 1972-73 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Nebraska
    - Abortion, 1973-81 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Minors, 1971, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Reproductive rights, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Nevada
    - Abortion, 1973-81 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Family planning, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Minors, 1976-77 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - New Hampshire
    - Abortion